- Tulip. - Tao.
- Tulip. - Tao.
Tulip, look out!
Tulip, awas!
Unit 24 received a report of someone falling down the overpass stairs.
Unit 24 menerima laporan ada orang jatuh dari tangga jembatan penyeberangan.
When we checked the scene, we found no injured person.
Saat kami memeriksa TKP, kami tidak menemukan korban luka.
You're not alone anymore.
Kamu tidak sendirian lagi.
Let's get through this together.
Mari kita lalui ini bersama-sama.
Baikhaw... you don't know her, right?
Baikhaw... kamu tidak mengenalnya, kan?
What about Baikhaw's mother?
Bagaimana dengan ibu Baikhaw?
No!
Tidak!
[Medical Record]
[Rekam Medis]
I missed you so much, little sister.
Aku sangat merindukanmu, adik kecil.
Wow, it smells so good.
Wah, baunya enak sekali.
Here you go! Oops!
Ini dia! Ups!
Easy.
Pelan-pelan.
- I'm gonna taste it now. - Go on.
- Aku mau mencicipinya sekarang. - Silakan.
Is it salty?
Apa keasinan?
- No. It's good. - Really? You like strong flavors, don't you?
- Tidak. Ini enak. - Benarkah? Kamu suka rasa yang kuat, ya?
But it's spicy.
Tapi ini pedas.
I love sodium, okay.
Aku suka yang asin-asin, tahu.
Baikhaw.
Baikhaw.
The Chairman approached me about the director position.
Ketua menawari Ayah posisi direktur.
You're sure everything about Baikhaw has been taken care of, right?
Ayah yakin semua urusan tentang Baikhaw sudah beres, kan?
Of course.
Tentu saja.
Good.
Bagus.
No more missteps.
Jangan ada kesalahan lagi.
[Motion Sensor]
[Sensor Gerak]
Hey!
Hei!
Our daughter!
Putri kita!
No one can take you away from me anymore.
Tidak ada yang bisa mengambilmu dariku lagi.
Your condition can be treated.
Penyakitmu itu bisa diobati.
- Let my mom... - Your mom is the reason I'm this way.
- Biar ibuku... - Ibumu adalah alasan aku jadi begini.
What did my mom do to you?
Apa yang ibuku lakukan padamu?
You idiot!
Dasar bodoh!
She still hasn't told you, has she?
Dia masih belum memberitahumu, ya?
What did my mom do to you?
Apa yang ibuku lakukan padamu?
Your parents... killed my father!
Orang tuamu... membunuh ayahku!
What did you just say?
Apa yang baru saja kau katakan?
How could you say something like that?
Tega sekali kau bicara seperti itu?
You're a mother yourself.
Kau sendiri seorang ibu.
You should understand how my wife and I feel.
Kau harusnya mengerti perasaan saya dan istri.
Hello?
Halo?
Damn it!
Sialan!
Why did you do this to my family?
Kenapa kalian melakukan ini pada keluargaku?
How could you do this?
Bagaimana bisa kalian melakukan ini?
Dad!
Ayah!
Dad, what's wrong?
Ayah, ada apa?
[Case Dismissed]
[Kasus Ditolak]
Dad!
Ayah!
Hello.
Halo.
Help me, please.
Tolong saya.
Someone has broken into my house.
Ada orang membobol rumah saya.
What the hell is wrong with you, Baikhaw? You're insane.
Apa yang salah denganmu, Baikhaw? Kau gila.
Then go ask your parents.
Tanya saja pada orang tuamu.
Ask them what they did to my family.
Tanya apa yang mereka lakukan pada keluargaku.
They've been lying to you all along.
Mereka membohongimu selama ini.
You're the one who lied to me.
Kamulah yang membohongiku.
You destroyed everyone.
Kau menghancurkan semua orang.
And now you're still messing with my head.
Dan sekarang kau masih mengacaukan pikiranku.
I don't believe anything you say anymore.
Aku tidak percaya apa pun ucapanmu lagi.
You don't believe me?
Kau tidak percaya padaku?
Or you just can't accept how screwed up your parents really are?
Atau kau hanya tak bisa menerima betapa brengseknya orang tuamu?
Huh?
Hah?
Officer, she's in the bathroom.
Pak, dia ada di kamar mandi.
Excuse me.
Permisi.
Lieutenant.
Letnan.
We've searched everywhere.
Kami sudah mencari ke mana-mana.
But we still haven't found Baikhaw.
Tapi kami masih belum menemukan Baikhaw.
We'll assign officers to increase security.
Kami akan menugaskan petugas untuk meningkatkan keamanan.
- If you'll excuse us. - Thank you.
- Kami permisi dulu. - Terima kasih.
They said they'll tighten security, sweetheart.
Mereka bilang akan memperketat keamanan, Sayang.
Okay?
Oke?
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Would you like to stay at the main house for now?
Apa kamu mau tinggal di rumah utama dulu?
It's okay.
Tidak apa-apa.
If the police keep checking in like this,
Jika polisi terus memeriksa seperti ini,
it should be fine.
seharusnya aman.
But I'm not at ease.
Tapi aku tidak tenang.
Right now, they still haven't caught her.
Saat ini, mereka masih belum menangkapnya.
Mom.
Ibu.
I'm asking you, really.
Aku bertanya padamu, sungguh.
You knew about Baikhaw's family, didn't you?
Ibu tahu tentang keluarga Baikhaw, kan?
I already know
Aku sudah tahu
that Baikhaw's mom was Dad's former patient.
bahwa ibu Baikhaw adalah mantan pasien Ayah.
Please stop lying to me.
Tolong berhenti membohongiku.
Baikhaw's mother had a miscarriage
Ibu Baikhaw mengalami keguguran
and blamed your father for it.
dan menyalahkan ayahmu karenanya.
Danai, you shit doctor!
Danai, dokter sialan!
Where are you?
Di mana kau?
What's going on here?
Ada apa ini?
Get over here.
Sini kau.
What did you do to my wife? Huh?
Apa yang kau lakukan pada istriku? Hah?
My wife miscarried because of you!
Istriku keguguran gara-gara kau!
What did you do?
Apa yang kau lakukan?
Let go!
Lepaskan!
But the truth is,
Tapi kenyataannya,
there had already been domestic violence in that family.
sudah terjadi kekerasan dalam rumah tangga di keluarga itu.
There were many witnesses all along.
Ada banyak saksi selama ini.
What kind of wife are you?
Istri macam apa kau?
Your husband hasn't even eaten, and instead of caring...
Suamimu belum makan, bukannya peduli...
Damn it!
Sialan!
He tried to sue your father,
Dia mencoba menuntut ayahmu,
but the court dismissed the case due to insufficient evidence.
tapi pengadilan menolak kasusnya karena kurang bukti.
That incident... severely damaged his reputation.
Kejadian itu... sangat merusak reputasinya.
After that...
Setelah itu...
he took his own life.
dia bunuh diri.
Baikhaw must have been furious at your father and me,
Baikhaw pasti sangat marah pada ayahmu dan Ibu,
which is why she took it out on you.
itulah sebabnya dia melampiaskannya padamu.
Then why didn't you tell me from the beginning?
Lalu kenapa Ibu tidak memberitahuku sejak awal?
Tulip...
Tulip...
I'm so sorry, sweetheart...
Maafkan Ibu, Sayang...
for making you go through all of this.
karena membuatmu melalui semua ini.
Tulip.
Tulip.
I heard that Baikhaw broke into your house. Is that true?
Aku dengar Baikhaw membobol rumahmu. Apa itu benar?
That's so scary.
Itu menakutkan sekali.
What did she say to you?
Apa yang dia katakan padamu?
Tell us. We are curious.
Ceritakan pada kami. Kami penasaran.
Are you actually worried, or just being nosy?
Kalian benar-benar khawatir, atau cuma kepo?
Of course, we're worried.
Tentu saja kami khawatir.
What you went through was serious.
Apa yang kau alami itu serius.
Then if you really care, can you not ask me right now?
Kalau kalian benar-benar peduli, bisakah jangan tanya sekarang?
I'm not ready to talk about it.
Aku belum siap membicarakannya.
Hey. Without us, you'd have no friends at all.
Hei. Tanpa kami, kau tak akan punya teman sama sekali.
Friends like you are better off not existing.
Teman seperti kalian lebih baik tidak ada.
Come on, Tulip.
Ayolah, Tulip.
What?
Apa?
What is this?
Apa ini?
I told you to stay away.
Sudah kubilang menjauhlah.
I can't stay out of it, Tulip.
Aku tidak bisa diam saja, Tulip.
I know about Baikhaw.
Aku tahu soal Baikhaw.
And I'm worried about you.
Dan aku mengkhawatirkanmu.
And when Baikhaw was manipulating me,
Dan saat Baikhaw memanipulasiku,
weren't you worried then?
apa kau khawatir saat itu?
Tulip, you already know how guilty I feel about all of this.
Tulip, kau sudah tahu betapa bersalahnya aku tentang semua ini.
I've already lost my scholarship.
Aku sudah kehilangan beasiswaku.
I've taken full responsibility for Namo's case.
Aku sudah bertanggung jawab penuh atas kasus Namo.
I've really tried to make up for everything.
Aku benar-benar mencoba menebus semuanya.
How much is ever going to be enough, Tao?
Berapa banyak yang akan cukup, Tao?
You caused Wawwa and Q to die.
Kau menyebabkan Wawwa dan Q mati.
Feeling guilty for life still wouldn't be enough.
Merasa bersalah seumur hidup pun masih belum cukup.
There's nothing I can do to change that.
Tidak ada yang bisa kulakukan untuk mengubahnya.
But right now, I can still protect you.
Tapi saat ini, aku masih bisa melindungimu.
Please, Tulip.
Tolong, Tulip.
I really want to make amends for what I've done.
Aku benar-benar ingin menebus apa yang telah kulakukan.
So you actually believed what he said?
Jadi kamu percaya apa yang dia katakan?
Tao knows Baikhaw better than anyone.
Tao mengenal Baikhaw lebih baik dari siapa pun.
Maybe he knows something we don't.
Mungkin dia tahu sesuatu yang kita tidak tahu.
And what do you want to know from him?
Dan apa yang ingin kamu ketahui darinya?
I don't think I can breathe again
Kurasa aku tidak bisa bernapas lega
until I figure out where Baikhaw is or what she's planning next.
sampai aku tahu di mana Baikhaw atau apa rencananya selanjutnya.
Honestly, I don't know that either.
Jujur, aku juga tidak tahu soal itu.
That's why we need to figure it out together.
Itu sebabnya kita perlu mencarinya bersama.
Am I supposed to keep looking over my shoulder forever?
Apa aku harus terus-terusan waspada selamanya?
So have the police gone to Baikhaw's house yet?
Jadi apa polisi sudah pergi ke rumah Baikhaw?
They did, but they didn't find anything.
Sudah, tapi mereka tidak menemukan apa-apa.
They only found Taew and Baikhaw's mom.
Mereka hanya menemukan Taew dan ibu Baikhaw.
Taew said that Baikhaw hasn't sent money for months.
Taew bilang Baikhaw sudah berbulan-bulan tidak mengirim uang.
She's only helping out of pity.
Dia hanya membantu karena kasihan.
Where the hell is she?
Di mana dia sebenarnya?
As for where she is, I do wonder about that.
Soal di mana dia, aku juga penasaran.
But what I'm more suspicious about is my mom.
Tapi yang lebih aku curigai adalah ibuku.
I don't think she has told me everything.
Kurasa dia belum menceritakan semuanya padaku.
What do you mean, Tulip?
Maksudmu apa, Tulip?
Even though Baikhaw lied to me about a lot of things,
Walaupun Baikhaw membohongiku tentang banyak hal,
there's one thing I believe.
ada satu hal yang kupercaya.
My mom would do anything to protect my dad.
Ibuku akan melakukan apa saja untuk melindungi ayahku.
I think...
Aku rasa...
she's definitely hiding something from me.
dia pasti menyembunyikan sesuatu dariku.
Otherwise, Baikhaw's family wouldn't have ended up like this.
Jika tidak, keluarga Baikhaw tidak akan berakhir seperti ini.
Sometimes I'm scared that
Terkadang aku takut bahwa
what Baikhaw said might actually be true.
apa yang dikatakan Baikhaw mungkin benar.
If we can't get answers from Tulip's parents...
Jika kita tidak bisa mendapat jawaban dari orang tua Tulip...
then why don't we find out ourselves?
kenapa kita tidak cari tahu sendiri?
Thank you for coming.
Terima kasih sudah datang.
I have to check on the house regularly anyway,
Saya memang harus rutin memeriksa rumah ini,
in case Baikhaw comes back to see her mother.
kalau-kalau Baikhaw kembali menemui ibunya.
But why do you want to go inside?
Tapi kenapa kalian ingin masuk?
I forgot my schoolbooks here.
Buku pelajaran saya tertinggal di sini.
I just need to grab them.
Saya hanya perlu mengambilnya.
Could you open the door for us, please?
Bisa tolong bukakan pintunya untuk kami?
Sure.
Tentu.
Go ahead.
Silakan.
The court ruling in the case where Baikhaw's father sued Tulip's father...
Putusan pengadilan dalam kasus di mana ayah Baikhaw menuntut ayah Tulip...
if we want to request a copy from the court,
jika kita ingin meminta salinannya dari pengadilan,
we'd need a power of attorney
kita butuh surat kuasa
or consent from Tulip's father first.
atau persetujuan dari ayah Tulip dulu.
Since we can't get it that way,
Karena kita tidak bisa mendapatkannya dengan cara itu,
this is the only place left to look.
ini satu-satunya tempat yang tersisa untuk mencari.
I believe Baikhaw must have kept it.
Aku yakin Baikhaw pasti menyimpannya.
And in there, we may find the real reason
Dan di sana, kita mungkin menemukan alasan sebenarnya
why Baikhaw hates Tulip's parents.
kenapa Baikhaw membenci orang tua Tulip.
Ma'am.
Bu.
- Are you here? - Guys!
- Ibu di sini? - Teman-teman!
Wait a moment.
Tunggu sebentar.
We need the homeowner's permission first.
Kita butuh izin pemilik rumah dulu.
Hello.
Halo.
Why are the police here?
Kenapa polisi ada di sini?
Baikhaw's friend said she came to pick up some books.
Teman Baikhaw bilang dia datang untuk mengambil beberapa buku.
She's not a friend.
Dia bukan teman.
This is Khawfang, Baikhaw's younger sister.
Ini Khawfang, adiknya Baikhaw.
- My child. - Ma'am! Ma'am!
- Anakku. - Bu! Bu!
- No, she's not. No. - Come here.
- Bukan, bukan. - Ke sini.
Where are you taking my child?
Mau kau bawa ke mana anakku?
- Ma'am... - Get out! Get out! Get out! Get out!
- Bu... - Keluar! Keluar! Keluar! Keluar!
No, no, we're not taking her anywhere.
Tidak, tidak, kami tidak membawanya ke mana-mana.
Mom, please calm down.
Bu, tolong tenang.
Easy, okay?
Tenang, ya?
Look...
Lihat...
They're my friends.
Mereka teman-temanku.
Where are you taking Khawfang?
Mau kau bawa ke mana Khawfang?
Please let my friends grab something quickly.
Izinkan teman-temanku mengambil sesuatu sebentar.
Your friends?
Teman-temanmu?
You guys go find what you need.
Kalian carilah apa yang kalian butuhkan.
Let's go rest, okay?
Ayo istirahat, ya?
Go, get out.
Pergi, keluar.
Go. Leave me alone.
Pergi. Tinggalkan aku sendiri.
Please sit down and rest.
Silakan duduk dan istirahat.
Khawfang, don't go out. Don't go.
Khawfang, jangan keluar. Jangan pergi.
They're going to take you away.
Mereka akan membawamu pergi.
Who?
Siapa?
Danai's people.
Orang-orang Danai.
Everyone's working for him, honey.
Semua orang bekerja untuknya, sayang.
Don't go.
Jangan pergi.
- Danai... - He...
- Danai... - Dia...
He almost took you from me.
Dia hampir mengambilmu dariku.
Danai... what did he do?
Danai... apa yang dia lakukan?
What did he do to you?
Apa yang dia lakukan padamu?
He... he...
Dia... dia...
Hey.
Hei.
What's going on with your friend?
Ada apa dengan temanmu?
It's probably nothing.
Mungkin bukan apa-apa.
We'll find what we need and leave right away.
Kami akan mencari yang kami butuhkan lalu segera pergi.
Alright, we'll check the house's perimeter.
Baiklah, kami akan memeriksa keliling rumah.
Okay.
Oke.
Let's go.
Ayo.
[Criminal Court Case]
[Kasus Pengadilan Pidana]
[Karoon Chanchaliaosap V Danai Pattarakorn]
[Karoon Chanchaliaosap V Danai Pattarakorn]
Tao!
Tao!
You found it?
Kamu menemukannya?
[Drove away without providing help]
[Pergi tanpa memberikan pertolongan]
[Physical and psychological harm caused the victim to later miscarry]
[Kekerasan fisik dan psikis menyebabkan korban kemudian keguguran]
[The victim suffered severe effects, resulting in psychiatric illness]
[Korban mengalami dampak parah, mengakibatkan penyakit kejiwaan]
[Insufficient evidence to convict...]
[Kurang bukti untuk menghukum...]
[Case Dismissed]
[Kasus Ditolak]
Tulip's mom really did lie.
Ibu Tulip benar-benar berbohong.
He... he...
Dia... dia...
What happened? Can you tell me?
Apa yang terjadi? Bisa ceritakan padaku?
He...
Dia...
[Ob-Gyn Department]
[Departemen Ob-Gyn]
I have an appointment.
Saya punya janji temu.
Yes, please wait a moment.
Ya, mohon tunggu sebentar.
Oh, Ms. Fah.
Oh, Bu Fah.
Hello, doctor.
Halo, dokter.
Hello.
Halo.
How have you been feeling?
Bagaimana perasaan Anda?
A bit uncomfortable, but I've been sleeping better.
Agak tidak nyaman, tapi saya sudah bisa tidur lebih nyenyak.
Then let's continue inside the exam room.
Mari kita lanjutkan di ruang periksa.
Okay.
Baik.
How have things been with your husband lately?
Bagaimana hubungan dengan suami akhir-akhir ini?
He's been irritable, probably stressed about work.
Dia mudah marah, mungkin stres soal pekerjaan.
But it hasn't turned physical.
Tapi tidak sampai main fisik.
I think the mother's mental health is very important.
Saya rasa kesehatan mental ibu sangat penting.
It would be good to talk things through with him.
Akan lebih baik jika dibicarakan baik-baik dengannya.
Yes.
Iya.
But you look even more beautiful.
Tapi Anda terlihat makin cantik.
You were already pretty to begin with.
Padahal dari awal sudah cantik.
Thank you.
Terima kasih.
Have you had sexual relations with your husband recently?
Apa Anda berhubungan seksual dengan suami baru-baru ini?
No.
Tidak.
Is your sexual desire still normal?
Apa hasrat seksual Anda masih normal?
A little, yes.
Sedikit, iya.
I'll examine you now.
Saya akan memeriksa Anda sekarang.
Ouch!
Aduh!
- It'll hurt a bit. - Doctor, what are you doing?
- Akan sakit sedikit. - Dokter, apa yang Anda lakukan?
I'm checking to see if there's anything abnormal.
Saya memeriksa apakah ada yang tidak normal.
Ow!
Aw!
Whoa! What the hell?
Wah! Apa-apaan?
What happened?
Apa yang terjadi?
Ow!
Aduh!
- Geez! - You hit someone! Go, hurry up, go!
- Astaga! - Kau menabrak orang! Pergi, cepat, pergi!
Ow!
Aduh!
Fah, are you okay?
Fah, kamu tidak apa-apa?
Fah!
Fah!
Are you okay?
Kamu tidak apa-apa?
Today, I...
Hari ini, aku...
- Ow! - Fah.
- Aduh! - Fah.
You're this far along and still having morning sickness?
Sudah sejauh ini dan masih mual pagi?
Ow!
Aduh!
Fah!
Fah!
Doctor, my wife is in severe pain.
Dokter, istri saya kesakitan hebat.
- She's bleeding. - My baby... my baby...
- Dia pendarahan. - Bayiku... bayiku...
- My baby... - Stay calm.
- Bayiku... - Tenanglah.
How is my baby?
Bagaimana bayiku?
Right now, the baby's heart has stopped beating.
Saat ini, jantung bayi sudah berhenti berdetak.
How is that possible?
Bagaimana mungkin?
My wife was just here for a check-up.
Istri saya baru saja periksa di sini.
There's still blood around the heart area.
Masih ada darah di sekitar area jantung.
It likely happened not long ago.
Kemungkinan baru saja terjadi.
Have you been counting fetal movements?
Apa Anda menghitung gerakan janin?
You didn't? I already taught you how.
Tidak? Saya sudah mengajari caranya.
If you had come in earlier,
Jika Anda datang lebih awal,
this might not have happened.
ini mungkin tidak terjadi.
Khawfang, my baby!
Khawfang, bayiku!
Khawfang!
Khawfang!
It's okay now, Khawfang.
Sudah tidak apa-apa sekarang, Khawfang.
Khawfang, my baby.
Khawfang, bayiku.
My name isn't Khawfang. I'm not Khawfang.
Namaku bukan Khawfang. Aku bukan Khawfang.
What are you talking about?
Kau bicara apa?
Khawfang... you are Khawfang, my baby.
Khawfang... kamu Khawfang, bayiku.
Khawfang, my baby.
Khawfang, bayiku.
My name is Tulip.
Namaku Tulip.
I'm not your daughter.
Aku bukan putrimu.
Tulip.
Tulip.
Tulip... Danai's daughter?
Tulip... anak Danai?
Danai's daughter?
Anak Danai?
Where's my child?
Di mana anakku?
Where is she?
Di mana dia?
Where is my child? Where?
Di mana anakku? Di mana?
Danai's child?
Anak Danai?
You're Danai's kid, aren't you?
Kau anaknya Danai, kan?
- Tulip!
- Tulip!
Tulip! Tulip!
Tulip! Tulip!
Danai's brat!
Anak nakal Danai!
Go! Now!
Pergi! Sekarang!
Where are you going?
Mau ke mana kau?
Run, Namo!
Lari, Namo!
Tulip!
Tulip!
Tulip! Tulip!
Tulip! Tulip!
Drop the weapon!
Jatuhkan senjatanya!
Come here!
Ke sini!
Hello, ma'am. I'm Namo.
Halo, Bu. Saya Namo.
Tulip's inside, right?
Tulip di dalam, kan?
Yes.
Ya.
And Tao?
Dan Tao?
Why did you leave me and Mom, Dad?
Kenapa Ayah meninggalkan aku dan Ibu?
Khawfang.
Khawfang.
Come sit with Mommy, sweetheart.
Sini duduk sama Ibu, sayang.
Baikhaw.
Baikhaw.
Baikhaw!
Baikhaw!
Come sit with me.
Sini duduk denganku.
Bring Khawfang with you.
Bawa Khawfang bersamamu.
Khawfang.
Khawfang.
Remember this, my baby.
Ingat ini, anakku.
They killed your little sister.
Mereka membunuh adikmu.
Because of them, this is what we've become.
Karena merekalah kita jadi seperti ini.
Mom.
Bu.
Where's Namo?
Di mana Namo?
Namo went to the police station to see Tao.
Namo pergi ke kantor polisi menemui Tao.
He should be back soon.
Dia harusnya segera kembali.
And... how is Baikhaw's mom?
Dan... bagaimana ibu Baikhaw?
She...
Dia...
lost too much blood.
kehilangan terlalu banyak darah.
She's gone now.
Dia sudah tiada.
But... but, Mom...
Tapi... tapi, Bu...
Tao didn't do it.
bukan Tao pelakunya.
Baikhaw's mom lunged at him herself.
Ibu Baikhaw menerjangnya sendiri.
Tao and Namo already told the police everything.
Tao dan Namo sudah menceritakan semuanya pada polisi.
I know everything now.
Aku tahu semuanya sekarang.
Know what?
Tahu apa?
Dad's case.
Kasus Ayah.
What Dad did...
Apa yang Ayah lakukan...
it really happened. I remember now.
itu benar-benar terjadi. Aku ingat sekarang.
- Sir... sir! - You fabricated this.
- Pak... Pak! - Kau mengarang ini.
You filed a complaint with the university, accusing me of losing control.
Kau mengajukan aduan ke universitas, menuduh saya kehilangan kendali.
Even though I've never treated a student that way.
Padahal saya tak pernah memperlakukan mahasiswa seperti itu.
Are you trying to threaten me into dropping the case against your husband?
Apa kau mencoba mengancamku untuk mencabut gugatan terhadap suamimu?
What happened to your wife is not my husband's fault.
Apa yang terjadi pada istrimu bukan salah suami saya.
If it's not, then that's bullshit.
Jika bukan, maka itu omong kosong.
So you're going to squeeze me from every angle, huh?
Jadi kau mau menekanku dari segala arah, hah?
Fine.
Baiklah.
If you want me fired, then I'll leave.
Jika kau ingin aku dipecat, aku akan keluar.
And I'll fight you in court.
Dan aku akan melawanmu di pengadilan.
Gladly.
Dengan senang hati.
Orderly! Orderly! Help, please!
Petugas! Petugas! Tolong!
Yes.
Ya.
- This way, please. - Please step outside.
- Lewat sini, tolong. - Silakan keluar.
- Outside, please. - Remember this! Remember it!
- Tolong keluar. - Ingat ini! Ingat!
Please.
Tolong.
The records from the day his wife came in
Catatan dari hari istrinya datang
have all been deleted, right?
sudah dihapus semua, kan?
All done.
Beres.
Baikhaw was probably abused by her own mother since she was a child...
Baikhaw mungkin disiksa oleh ibunya sendiri sejak kecil...
because of Dad and you.
karena Ayah dan Ibu.
You're the reason Baikhaw ended up like this.
Kalianlah alasan Baikhaw jadi seperti ini.
Tulip!
Tulip!
What are you talking about?
Apa yang kamu bicarakan?
You're just mixing things up now.
Kamu cuma mencampuradukkan masalah sekarang.
Then tell me this.
Kalau begitu jawab ini.
Say that Dad didn't do it.
Katakan Ayah tidak melakukannya.
Things have already gone this far.
Semuanya sudah sejauh ini.
Tulip!
Tulip!
That's not it.
Bukan begitu.
If that's not true...
Jika itu tidak benar...
then why, that day,
lalu kenapa, hari itu,
did you order Baikhaw's mom's medical records to be deleted?
Ibu menyuruh rekam medis ibu Baikhaw dihapus?
If Dad didn't do anything, why would you do that?
Jika Ayah tidak melakukan apa-apa, kenapa Ibu melakukan itu?
Why pretend Dad did nothing to Baikhaw's mom?
Kenapa pura-pura Ayah tidak melakukan apa-apa pada ibu Baikhaw?
Tulip, I'm sorry.
Tulip, Ibu minta maaf.
- I'm sorry. - Let go.
- Ibu minta maaf. - Lepaskan.
Please leave.
Tolong keluar.
- Tulip... - I want to be alone.
- Tulip... - Aku ingin sendiri.
Tulip, honey.
Tulip, sayang.
Do you want to go out and get something to eat?
Mau keluar cari makan?
I'm tired.
Aku lelah.
I want to rest.
Aku ingin istirahat.
She's acting up.
Dia mulai lagi.
Aren't you going to do anything?
Kau tak akan melakukan sesuatu?
Tulip.
Tulip.
Don't walk away from me like this.
Jangan pergi begitu saja dariku.
From now on, come straight home after class.
Mulai sekarang, langsung pulang setelah kuliah.
Stop all university activities.
Hentikan semua kegiatan universitas.
I'll screen every one of your friends,
Ayah akan menyeleksi setiap temanmu,
so you won't hang out with psychos again.
supaya kamu tak bergaul dengan orang gila lagi.
What's so funny, huh?
Apa yang lucu, hah?
After everything that's happened,
Setelah semua yang terjadi,
you still don't feel any remorse at all, do you?
Ayah masih tidak merasa menyesal sama sekali, ya?
You don't even have the courage
Ayah bahkan tidak punya keberanian
to take responsibility for what you did.
untuk bertanggung jawab atas perbuatan Ayah.
And what do you think you're doing, trying to protect me?
Dan apa yang Ayah pikir Ayah lakukan, mencoba melindungiku?
Do you and Mom even realize what you did to another family?
Apa Ayah dan Ibu sadar apa yang kalian lakukan pada keluarga lain?
Now it's all come back to hurt me.
Sekarang semuanya berbalik menyakitiku.
Do you see what I've had to go through?
Apa kalian lihat apa yang harus kulalui?
If you had just listened to your parents,
Kalau saja kamu mendengarkan orang tuamu,
- none of this would've happened. - Fine!
- semua ini tak akan terjadi. - Baiklah!
It's all my fault... every damn thing.
Ini semua salahku... semuanya.
And the biggest mistake of all
Dan kesalahan terbesar dari semuanya
was being born to parents like you.
adalah terlahir dari orang tua seperti kalian.
You deal with our daughter.
Kau uruslah putri kita.
I'm busy enough with my job transfer.
Aku sudah cukup sibuk dengan mutasi kerjaku.
I don't have time for this nonsense.
Aku tak punya waktu untuk omong kosong ini.
No!
Tidak!
I'm not doing anything.
Aku tidak akan melakukan apa-apa.
From now on...
Mulai sekarang...
I'll only do my duty to protect my family
Aku hanya akan melakukan tugas melindungi keluargaku,
regardless of whether "family" includes you or not.
terlepas apakah "keluarga" itu termasuk kau atau tidak.
I don't think I can stay here anymore, Namo.
Kurasa aku tidak bisa tinggal di sini lagi, Namo.
I'll come pick you up.
Aku akan menjemputmu.
Okay.
Oke.
I found this over there.
Saya menemukan ini di sana.
Did you forget to pack it?
Apa Anda lupa mengemasnya?
Just leave it here.
Tinggalkan saja di sini.
Baikhaw.
Baikhaw.
I know the whole truth now.
Aku tahu semua kebenarannya sekarang.
I'm sorry.
Aku minta maaf.
- I'm sorry on behalf of my parents... - Isn't that a little too easy?
- Aku minta maaf atas nama orang tuaku... - Bukankah itu terlalu mudah?
What else do you want me to do?
Apa lagi yang kau ingin aku lakukan?
I'm sorry.
Aku minta maaf.
You can get better.
Kau bisa sembuh.
- I can help you. - Why would you help me?
- Aku bisa membantumu. - Kenapa kau mau membantuku?
I have no one left now.
Aku tidak punya siapa-siapa lagi sekarang.
Your parents shouldn't have anyone left either.
Orang tuamu juga seharusnya tidak punya siapa-siapa lagi.
It's just when I'm with you, it feels like we're sisters or something.
Hanya saja saat bersamamu, rasanya kita seperti saudara.
- Then call me "P'Baikhaw". - Yes, P'Baikhaw.
- Kalau begitu panggil aku "Kak Baikhaw". - Baik, Kak Baikhaw.
I thought you were so cool.
Kupikir Kakak keren banget.
What's with you?
Ada apa denganmu?
Can I be your Stan?
Boleh aku ngefans sama Kakak?
Ew, no... that's scary.
Ih, jangan... itu menakutkan.
Oh, come on.
Ah, ayolah.
[Several Months Later]
[Beberapa Bulan Kemudian]
I've got a new place now.
Aku punya tempat baru sekarang.
I'm moving in today.
Aku pindah hari ini.
My life... I can't say it's full of happiness.
Hidupku... Aku tak bisa bilang penuh kebahagiaan.
[Mutual-Consent Divorce Agreement]
[Surat Perjanjian Cerai Bersama]
There are people who come in,
Ada orang yang datang,
[Mr. Danai Pattarakorn]
[Tn. Danai Pattarakorn]
And people who leave.
Dan orang yang pergi.
There are enemies who may not be friends right now...
Ada musuh yang mungkin bukan teman saat ini...
but in the future, they might become friends.
tapi di masa depan, mereka mungkin jadi teman.
Tulip.
Tulip.
Namo.
Namo.
And there are people you never thought you could be friends with,
Dan ada orang yang tak pernah kau duga bisa jadi teman,
who end up becoming someone special.
yang akhirnya menjadi seseorang yang istimewa.
Want to go get something to eat?
Mau pergi cari makan?
Yeah, let's go.
Ya, ayo.
But no matter how it turns out, life is still life.
Tapi bagaimanapun jadinya, hidup tetaplah hidup.
And I've decided that I'll live my life just trying to be happy.
Dan aku memutuskan bahwa aku akan menjalani hidup hanya mencoba bahagia.
At least, I hope so.
Setidaknya, aku berharap begitu.